KIODOUR BROWN

347-323-1415 · <u>kiodour.b@gmail.com</u> · New York https://www.linkedin.com/in/kiodour/

CAREER PROFILE

I am an experienced **BIM Manager** with over 10+ years of AEC industry experience. I've worked in various roles in the industry; *Detailer*, *3D modeler*, *Rendering artist*, *BIM Specialist* & *BIM Coordinator*. Proficient in BIM/VDC best practices, MEP Coordination, software tools & techniques. I can collaborate well with the design team, MEP trades, and ownership to solve any issue that may affect the project schedule.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CSA Group NY Architects & Engineers, NY

March 2021 - Present

BIM Manager / DSNY S1 1/3 – Staten Island Garage (Est. 123M - 207,000 SF)

- Responsible for reviewing the BIM Execution Plan (BXP) and ensuring all stakeholders understand their roles & responsibilities.
- Responsible for coordinating weekly BIM meetings with the design team & ownership to review and resolve design issues that could affect the contractors' schedule.
- Responsible for reviewing Bulletins and ensure updated design changes are reflected in the BIM model.
- Responsible for ensuring the BIM deliverables are met to the specification outlined in the contract, i.e., LOD 400 clash-free model, Shop drawings & Asset data.
- Responsible for working closely with the Project Management team to identify & resolve issues that may cause delays.
- Responsible for helping reduce the number of Coordination Issues & RFIs by proactively coordinating with the design team to resolve design issues via teams meeting, phone & email.
- Point of contact for BIM-related queries from DDC (Department of Design & Construction).

BIM/VDC Consultant

July 2020 – March 2021

- Provide over-the-shoulder training to AEC Project Managers and students via Zoom on leveraging BIM methodologies.
- Helped a NY-based BIM Contractor to coordinate MEP trades for a boiler room.

CM & Associates Construction Management LLC, NY

Sep 2015 – Jul 2020

- Provide company-wide technical support for all BIM-related queries, including BIM/VDC workflows & best practices.
- Develop and implement company-wide BIM Scope-of-work template that is used on all new MEP Coordination projects.

BIM Coordinator / CORTE - 44th Drive LIC (8 Story Condo: 137,000 SF)

- Responsible for Developing BIM Execution Plan.
- Responsible for Drafting SOW & vet BIM Contractors during the bidding process.
- Responsible for leading weekly BIM MEP coordination meetings with project team members.
- Responsible for coordinating with the Site Superintendent for last-minute on-site changes.

KIODOUR BROWN

347-323-1415 · <u>kiodour.b@gmail.com</u> · New York https://www.linkedin.com/in/kiodour/

BIM Coordinator / 287 PARK AVE SOUTH (111,000 SF - Office Reno)

- Responsible for developing BIM Execution Plan and ensure that all stakeholders understand their roles on the project.
- Responsible for troubleshooting the Point Cloud model of existing conditions and ensure the said model is scaled appropriately with accurate geolocation.
- Responsible for Modeling & Coordinating Electrical shafts & Conduits around existing conditions and other trades.
- Responsible for Generating Clash Reports and Coordination Issues using Navisworks so that the design team and MEP trades can address the issues.

BIM Specialist /THE LINDLEY (95,000 SF, 74 apt, 20 Story condo)

- Responsible for modeling & coordinating all MEP trades using Revit & Navisworks
- Responsible for preparing and presenting clash reports & RFIs to relevant stakeholders.
- Responsible for producing shop drawings generated from MEP coordinated model.

BIM/CAD Detailer / STEINER EAST VILLAGE (7 Story Condo - 152,148 SF)

- Responsible for creating structural 3D Revit model & shops drawings using Revit.
- Produced concrete takeoffs (column/beam count & volume).
- Responsible for communicating last-minute coordination issues with Site Superintendent
- Responsible for technical leadership to effectively steer BIM efforts on future projects.

Hastings & Associates LLC, Jamaica

2010 - 2014

- Responsible for producing shop drawings for numerous residential & small commercial projects using AutoCAD Architecture & Revit.
- Responsible for creating realistic 3D renderings using Sketchup, Revit, 3DS Max + Vray

SOFTWARE SKILLS

- Revit
- Navisworks
- BIM 360/Glue
- AutoCAD

- Submittal Exchange -Primavera
- Procore
- Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator
- Bluebeam Revu

EDUCATION + TRAINING

- Excelsior Community College (Kingston, Jamaica), 2yr Vocational Construction Technology Certificate
- OSHA 30, New York